This is Mattio Conti. He's a 7-year
market maker, member of world-class
edge, and chief investment officer at
SQR Capital, a quantitative [music]
hedge fund. But I brought him in to
answer one question. How would a quant
hedge fund exploit the mathematics of
prop firms? His answer was a systematic
VWAP strategy he built that produced
over 300%
across more than 4,000 trades in
historical testing.
>> This one strategy that I would run is
what I call the drift VWAP pullback. And
this is a very simple long short
strategy. Like the reason why this
strategy is extremely good for prop
firms is this number right here. So,
this strategy uh profitability rate,
which is of 64%.
>> But VWAP alone isn't the real edge.
Mattio specifically built this strategy
around the execution algorithms used
inside banks and brokerages. Using what
he learned as a market maker to identify
when institutional buying and selling
pressure exposes itself. And by
identifying this exact edge, he built a
strategy with a simulated 93.6%
chance of getting funded within only
four attempts.
>> The imbalance between
uh the amount of algorithms that are
selling and amount of algorithms that
are buying gets actually revealed and
you have like these sharp movements both
in the downside or the upside. And this
is what we are trying to exploit right
here. We are trying to exploit exactly
this behavior. By the time you use this
exact same [music] strategy within four
challenges, you have a 93.6%
of passing at least one. And that's why
the the people I work with, the people
in my community, they call it prop firm
golden ticket because if you change
>> In this episode, Matteo reveals the
exact day trading VWAP strategy his
community calls the prop firm golden
ticket live on the chart and exposes the
number one discipline [music] that
separates decent traders from great
ones. Nothing in this video is financial
advice. We're here to study how one of
the most sophisticated traders we've
ever interviewed actually executes. Now,
let's see what Matteo is made of.
Matteo, you spent years as a market
maker at Nordea Markets and today you
run systematic strategies at SQR
Capital. Obviously, this is
institutional experience that goes well
beyond almost every guest I've had here.
Now, what did this experience teach you
about trading profitably that most
retail traders fundamentally
misunderstand?
>> Yeah. First of all, thank you so much
for having me here. It is truly a
pleasure. Like every time that someone
gives me a platform to talk about this,
I find it extremely exciting.
And the biggest misconception is that
people are obsessed
looking after trades. They want to find
the next trade and they want that the
next trade is profitable. On the other
hand, institutional traders are obsessed
going after profitable trading
strategies. This is the whole difference
between
institutional trading and retail
trading.
>> So, fundamentally then focusing on a
profitable strategy would be thinking
over hundreds and hundreds and hundreds
of trades over years potentially instead
of looking for the next big setup,
right? So, this kind of brings us into
then, Matteo,
How do you know that a a strategy is
actually profitable or has an edge?
>> Yeah, you need to test. And this is one
of the steps that retail traders often
skips because trading is actually about
getting an idea around your trading
strategy. It's about gathering data.
It's about encoding your trading
strategy and then applying that piece of
code to historical data so that you can
do your back test checking if in the
past that strategy is profitable and
afterwards running simulations.
Simulations that give you the confidence
that the strategy is truly profitable
and can make you money in the future.
>> Okay, so I want to unpack all of this
later in specific and specifically when
we get on the chart. You'll be able to
show us an example of this approach when
we get on the chart, right?
>> Yeah, and to some degree because like
one thing that I want to bring you here
given the fact that it's like uh um
um it's not that we want to have a
strategy that is necessary going to make
you money with your own capital and we
are in a prop firm context. I decided to
bring something here a strategy that
maximize the probabilities of actually
getting funded of passing a prop firm
challenge.
>> Excellent, Matteo. Thank you so much. I
want to keep talking about this, but I
think that we should get on the chart
and see exactly how we can step into
this arena that, you know, you've been
trading in now for a while. So, if you
don't mind, if you want to share your
screen and let's see what you got.
>> 100%
>> Matteo, we're on the chart. This looks
like multi-charts, which is a very
sophisticated piece of software. But
what exactly are you looking at here?
>> So, right here is uh I just loaded uh
two graphs. Uh one is uh Nasdaq 100
futures using a 5-minute time frame.
And here is Nasdaq 100 futures using a
50-minute time frame. But then, let me
give you a little bit of context because
mhm the strategy that I want to bring
here
answers the question that I've been
getting so many times. Like uh many
people uh many retail traders have been
asking me, "Mhm You as an institutional
traders, what is that one strategy that
you would run to pass prop firm
challenges?" And that's what I want to
bring here on this platform today. Uh
the answer to that question. Um this one
strategy that I would run is what I call
the drift VWAP pullback.
And this is a very simple long-short
strategy
which I specifically designed to pass
prop firm challenges.
>> Well, I'm excited to see it. I mean, I
had no clue that this is what we we were
going to do. So, please continue.
>> Yeah, okay. And and specifically I this
this strategy has been used by many
people that are followed like young
retail traders to actually getting
funded. And um
they're getting like so so many good
results that actually we call it a day
prop firm golden tickets and you will
shortly see why. Um the beauty of this
strategy as I say is like is extremely
simple. And it has its foundation on the
behavior of execution traders inside
banks and brokerage.
Mhm So, like the the why the why this
strategy that I'm going to show you is
actually working and it it it has like
it is rooted on actual market
microstructure. And that's what makes it
look quite
interesting and quite
appealing for for this case.
To trade it, we need to load the
5-minute charts of Nasdaq 100 futures,
and we need to load the 15-minute chart
of Nasdaq 100 futures as well. The third
component, given especially the name of
the drift VWAP
pullback, what we need to add is the
VWAP.
Which you will see appearing on our
charts right here.
>> [snorts]
>> The VWAP, this specific VWAP, this
specific VWAP displayed here, it is a
VWAP based on the 15-minute
chart, yet displayed on the top of the
5-minutes. And this is why we loaded
both the historical
time series.
First of all, like we need to to give
some information as well, like
what is the VWAP and why it matters. The
VWAP is the average price of everything
traded up to that specific point.
Weighted by the volume. So, it's like um
the price where the largest amount of
money actually changed hands. Do you
follow so far?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah, and why it is relevant.
Not sure if you're aware, but like
inside banks and brokerage houses, there
is a figure called the execution trader.
And the job of the execution trader is
just taking the orders from the
portfolio manager, which is the fund
manager, the hedge fund manager, the
actual person that is managing the
capital, and executing their trades.
Mhm, 90 to 95%
of these orders are executed using VWAP
execution algorithms. So, algorithms
that they are targeting the execution
around the VWAP.
Mhm, this this behavior, the fact that
so many execution traders are using this
specific algorithm,
has a very important consequence. So,
when the price
pulls back towards the VWAP,
there is a very intense trading activity
of these execution algorithms.
And this activity has the tendency, if
there is like if the sellers are in
control, if there is more
selling algorithms than buying
algorithms, there is going to be a push
down from the VWAP price. On the other
the opposite, if we have like a pullback
towards the VWAP, yet the buyers are in
control, there is going to be a pushback
uh on the upside. So, on a very high
level, what this strategy is doing and
what you should do as a trader is
keeping an eye on the VWAP price, which
is anchored at the uh market open, so
9:30 Eastern Time,
and
using it
using the VWAP to understand what is the
bias of the day, if there is more
selling pressure, so uh negative drift
or a positive drift, and that's what is
defined in this indicator with the red
uh crosses versus the green crosses. And
then once you have this pullback towards
the VWAP, then if is from the upside,
you go long. If is on the downside, you
go short. This is on a very high level
what the drift VWAP pullback is doing.
If we need to put it down in just one
sentence, it waits the
uh
for the 15-minutes charts to show a
clear established move in one direction.
For example, here we have a clear um
downtrend.
And um
more specifically, to translate it this
one into data, we use the VWAP tool to
identify these these move and these
downtrend.
And then we buy or we sell at the first
pullback towards the
uh VWAP price. If again is from the
lower side to
uh towards the higher side, and we have
this
uh pullback, we go short. On the other
side, if we have this pullback from the
upside towards the VWAP, and there is
a
positive deep trend on the VWAP, we go
long. This is like on a nutshell what is
doing.
>> These pullbacks and bounces off the
VWAP, what is the exact mechanic going
on there? Right when price
hits VWAP and then bounces off of it,
what is the mechanic?
>> Yeah, the mechanic is really like uh
once you get closer to the VWAP, there
is a lot of trading activity. The
trading activity of these algorithms is
going to intensify because they are more
certain than they're going to get filled
closer to the VWAP, right? And that's
why like it here around these points
where we are closer to the VWAP, the
imbalance between
the amount of algorithms that are
selling and the amount of algorithms
that are buying gets actually revealed
and you have like these sharp movements
both in the downside or the upside.
And and that this is and this is what
we're trying to exploit right here.
>> Now that we understand the philosophy
and the why,
are we able to systematically define an
exact entry point
in inside of this model? And how would
you do that?
>> This is this is my job. Like translating
everything in a in a systematic
quantitative systems. But yeah, so
basically like every 15 minutes and here
we go back to our 15-minute chart, we
ask the question, is there a trend?
And the three conditions that must be
true
to
answer the question yes or no
are going to be if we take like for the
long side first. Let's take the long.
For the long,
we need to have the
uh
price
above the VWAP.
Condition number one. Condition number
two, we need to have the VWAP that is
rising
over the past
15 minutes.
So that's why like when
the cross is green, means that the VWAP
from the past 15 minutes is increasing
and that's uh condition number two. And
condition number three is that over the
past 1 hour
the NQ price increased
at least 0.
1%.
And these are the three conditions to
that give tell us is there a positive
trend, is there a drift that we should
pay attention to. This one for the long.
Equally like
for the short
it's going to be
short. So, price below the VWAP, VWAP
falling over the past 15 minutes,
and over the past 1 hour the price of NQ
decreased
at least 0.1%. Let's change color to
red. And that These are basically like
just the condition that are telling us,
"Okay, are we in this downtrend? Are we
in on this uptrend?" And uh
many of these, apart from the third one
of the condition of the increase over
the past uh
4 15-minute bar, which is 1 hour,
and needs to be higher of 0.1%
or um
smaller than minus 0.1%,
like are all identified with these VWAP.
And an additional very important rule is
that on the first hour, so from 9:30
Eastern Time to 10:30 Eastern Time, we
are not going to trade because we want
to give the market time to give us
levels for the VWAP. We need to
understand where is the money that
actually exchange uh hands over the past
first hour.
Um say that once we identify the trend,
so let's say it's after half past 10
here,
we wait
so they trigger our trade.
We call it trigger.
It's going to be
the
first
So, the trigger for the longs
first um
red candle
towards the VWAP.
So, as we have a as we have a red candle
that pulls towards the VWAP,
then we open our long position. And as
opposite for the shorts,
first
green candle
after all the three conditions have been
satisfied, the three condition that
we've seen.
>> Real quick, for this long or this short,
is this going to be on a limit order at
the VWAP or at the close of the candle?
>> At the At the it's going to be at the
opening of the next candle. So, you as
the candle closes, you send a market
order.
>> Excellent. Please continue.
>> So, this one is going to be our trigger.
Once we have the pullback, the first
pullback, it doesn't matter how close it
is to the VWAP. As we have the pullback,
we try to get the short. Uh about risk
management and exit conditions, this is
>> Before we get there, I do have to have
have to ask you this for the audience.
>> Sure.
>> These These three rules, right, and then
the trigger. How did you come up with
this as being a a good rule set to
follow? Why these three specific rules?
>> Ever thought about getting into prop
trading? Perfect timing. Right now, we
have a huge offer for you. You can grab
a 50K futures challenge for just nine
bucks. Or if that's still too much, the
10K crypto challenge for only a single
dollar. Links in the description. And
now, back to the video.
>> Because these three specific rules, they
give you the level, they give you the
direction, and they give you the speed.
That's why I want that the three of them
are going to be satisfied at the same
time. And obviously, like again, I've
been a market maker for 7 years, so like
I do have a lot of understanding and
knowledge behind of how
things works, especially with the
execution of view up. And I know that
for these specific pullbacks, if we are
below if the price closes often below
the view up,
um
there is the present of high uh selling
activity.
Uh if um mm
the view up keeps decreasing, means that
we have a clear drift on the price. And
uh obviously, like what is like uh the
0.1%?
Uh it has been defined doing doing an
optimization in our in-sample data. We
will get there as well to talk about it,
because like uh this specific strategy
has been developed using data between
2020 to 2024. And this uh 0.1%
was the
um
optimal parameters uh minimizing the
risk of over fitting uh to to run this
specific strategy. That's how you get
them.
>> You do have supporting data then for
this model? And if you do, we'll talk
about it later. We'll get into the exits
first. But I just wanted to clarify if
if there was.
>> Yeah, yeah. Yeah, the uh this strategy
has been developed using an in-sample
data, as I said, between 2020 and 2024.
And uh it has been used over the past 6
months to pass many prop firm
challenges. And we will get there as
well why this one is so good to pass
prop firm challenges. And the
answer is behind the data. It's like
it's a strategy that really fits well
the mathematics of prop firms. It's
exciting stuff if you're a nerd like me.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay, please. Let's Let's go over exits
and risk management.
>> Yes, sir. And about the exits,
um we we left like
for the longs or risk management. So,
for the long we will put at risk
80 points to make
40 points.
So, as you can see is a very low reward
to risk ratio. And for the shorts, we
have
at risk 80 points to make for 50 points.
So, here as well we have a
negative
RR, as the retail traders say.
Um
so, and let's uh
Let's This one is going to be
our conditions to open and close a day
position. And lastly, we have importance
uh
guardrails.
Cuz we need to have the last set of
rules to make this strategy
properly
systematic, properly mechanical.
So, guardrails.
And these are one position at a time.
Max four trades
a day.
Max two
losses a day. So, if you have two
consecutive trades that are losing
trades for the day, we stop trading it.
>> [snorts]
>> And um, um, no new trades after
3:30
p.m.
Eastern time.
And uh, close all position
at
3:55
p.m. Eastern time. So, before regular
trading hours closes. And this is the
last set of rules that we really want to
include. Um,
the maximum two losses a day, maximum
four trades a day
is because uh, it's very hard to snipe
what is the exact moment that it will
revert or like when you will have this
pullback. And if number four, like in
sample, again, during the development
process of this strategy was showing
that was the optimal um, number of
trades to maximize the probabilities of
passing a proper challenge. If we get
uh, let's now
um, get uh,
the strategy in place like because one
thing that is very important is like the
fact that we set all these rules this
clearly allow us to translate the
strategy on a piece of code. This is so
much key because at that point we
translate the strategy in the piece of
code, we can apply it to our data. In
this case, I will only have uh, trading
one single trade. So, like a maximum
trade per day I put one, so we start
seeing on a visual point of view how one
trade will look.
And if we open
the list of trades,
let's take someone.
So, here you can see that we have this
positive drift.
So, we have the price above the view up
price.
Uh we have the VWAP that is increasing,
right? So, over the past 15 minutes, it
has been increasing. And we have the
price of the underlying asset, so of um
NASDAQ that over the past hour increased
more than 0.1%. So, all we did here was
waiting for the pullback towards the
VWAP and opening a long at the
at the
beginning of this opening of this bar.
And this one ended up in the in the
money. If we Again, this one is like all
the trades are applied over the our
entire period because we encoded our
strategy. So, it's not that we are
backtesting manually like I've seen them
doing it online. But,
this is one of the advantages of
coding everything.
So, as you can see here, it's well.
So, we have a negative trend, right?
We have the
VWAP that is decreasing.
And here we have a very tiny pullback.
But, it is a positive pullback because
it's the first positive bar. So, we open
the short position and ended up in the
money. So, this one is like
how it works
how it looks visually. And
it should give you a good grasp of this
concept of like we get the pullback
towards the VWAP. Then, if all the three
conditions are met, we open the short or
we open the long and we let the computer
doing this magic. As I was saying,
the optimal number of trades or maximum
number of trades is four.
So, let's change that parameters and
let's apply. Here we have four trades in
this consecutively, where we have like
three wins and one loss. So, and the the
beauty is that now we can have a look at
how this strategy
performed over the entire period. And
this is the performance. This is the
equity curve of this strategy since
2021. And as I said, like this strategy
has been developed only using data up to
2024. So, like from 2024 to yesterday,
the second of August 2026,
all of these is completely out of sample
performance.
Um so, it's not a matter of overfitting
and the entire strategy. And uh I
>> Matteo, why you make that point right
there though? In sample, out of sample,
overfitting. I know there's going to be
a lot of people watching who don't
understand those three. Now, we could
talk about it for 2 hours, but if you
had to simply break it down, why is
overfitting bad and why do you need to
test in sample and out of sample?
>> Yeah, so overfitting is bad because can
fool you making you think that you have
the best strategy in the world, like you
have an equity curve that is a straight
line that just keeps rising. When
actually, the reason why you have that
performance is because you added too
many rules, too many conditions, and you
over optimized your parameters. So, you
cherry picked the values of your inputs,
like what is the best take profit level,
what is the best stop loss level that I
should use to make this strategy looks
very good
in the past. But all it does overfitting
is like making your strategy look in the
past, but once you run it on unseen
data, the strategy gets completely
destroyed.
Um on the other hand,
if you take your data and you split your
data, let's say we have data from 2021
to 2026, we split the data exactly in
the middle, and we only do the research.
Like we add the our conditions. We
change the parameters only on the first
half. And then like we apply
the parameters that we defined on the
first half frozen in time on all the
unseen data. And then we check what is
the performance. And in this case like
we applied the we did this research on
data until 2024. We applied this
the same inputs from 2024 to 2025. Back
then was
and was looking at good performance.
Great.
Uprising in sample, uprising out of
sample. The probability that we are over
fitting are little. This is the very
first check that you should do in your
development process. But say that like
the reason why
this strategy is extremely good for prop
firms is this number right here. So this
strategy has a profitability rate which
is of 64%.
Which is extremely high. And it is
extremely high on the back obviously of
the fact that we have a low reward to
risk ratio. But
even though this strategy has a very
little average trade. So if you try to
apply this strategy on a
private account on running it with your
own money, this strategy is unlikely
that it's going to make you money with
your own capital. Yet the fact that it
has
as an average winning rate when it is
right 866,
and when it loses 1,300,
yet on the back of a 65%
profitability rate, this strategy makes
it extremely good to pass prop firm
challenges.
It's not Matteo that is just saying
that, but is uh um
is uh statistics and he's running
simulations on the back of this data.
Because what you can do is downloading
all the trades since 2020, 2021
and feed them to a um piece of code to
to Python where you code that uh model
to run simulations, understand what is
the actual probability of passing a prop
firm challenge. And this is what I did
and this is what I'm going to show you
on um right now. [clears throat] And
here it is. Here is like what I did was
just taking all the trades that you have
just seen.
I wrote a small piece of code on Python
to run 20,000 simulations and give me as
a feedback what is the actual
probability that I pass a prop firm
challenge using this specific strategy.
And uh
the single passing rate of any single
prop firm challenge of this strategy is
50% or 49.8%
meaning that if you take uh
one prop firm challenge and you run this
exact set of rules, you have a 50%
probability of passing it with an
average time to pass of approximately 3
days.
Where it gets interesting though
is that yes, using one contract of NQ or
10 micro NQs,
um you have a pass rate of 49.8%.
You have an average days to pass 3.4, so
you are way within the limits of the 20
trading days. And um um
what makes it interesting is that if you
only take one challenge and you apply
this specific strategy, you have a 49.8%
probability.
But you have a 74.8%
to pass a prop firm challenge within two
attempts. And a 87.3%
to pass at least one challenge within
three attempts.
By the time you use this exact same
strategy within four
challenges, you have a 93.6%
of passing at least one. And that's why
the people I work with, the people in my
community, they call it the
prop firm golden ticket. Because if you
change the way you approach with prop
firm and you start looking at at it like
as a
business almost, you know that now,
let's say each prop firm challenge costs
$50.
Now you're spending at maximum $200,
you are almost guaranteed with a 93.6%
to get funded on at least one of those
accounts. And once you're funded,
you will need to look for a strategy
which maximizes the probabilities to get
a payout. And that one is going to be a
conversation maybe on the next
interview.
>> So so Mateo, let me clarify for the
audience. You know, there's a lot of
hoopla in the trading scene and people
think there's like 90% win rates with
like 10 to one reward risks. This
doesn't happen. So if on your first
challenge, you theoretically have a
50/50 chance using a strategy, that is
very that is very very good because I
have the numbers, I've seen it all.
Way less than 50% of people pass a
challenge. It's beautiful. I love it.
Trust me, I want to sit here and nerd
out about it with you. This is the stuff
I do, too, but so before we jump off the
chart, Matteo, I
>> Yes, sir.
>> I want to make it clear to the audience,
a lot of this is going to be beyond what
they are naturally capable of doing.
So,
is this strategy able to be traded
manually, or would you not recommend
that?
>> The issue of trading manually is that
you really need to be very diligent, but
um if you want to trade it manually, you
can just still have it encoded
and waiting for the trigger. That's how
I would do it. Like in the in any case,
like you have the trigger, you say,
"Okay, I trade it." And then you enter
your trade manually. Trying to beat
there to
eyeball it, it might work, it might not
work, but you don't have the confidence
of knowing that your strategy is going
to have 50% probability of passing you
the challenge. And that's what
automation really gives you. This is the
big advantage of like saying,
"I have it encoded at least then." If
you want to trade it manually on the
back of the signal that you receive from
your machine,
that's already one step forward that
virtually any retail trader in 2026
can actually achieve.
Um if you go a little bit further and
you manage to even automate the entire
full process,
it's not that you're going to run one
strategy, you're going to run a set of
three, four trading strategies that will
help you to make you money either on a
prop firm context or with your own
capital. And that's where you really
start growing as a trader.
>> So, Matteo, before we jump off the
chart, if you're going to take this
seriously, trading in general or a
strategy like this, you should start
working yourself up to being able to
automate.
>> 100%, but that's the trend. We will like
as as retail traders understand that it
makes no sense that you have a computer
in front of you and you're leveraging
the hell out of it.
Like
as people understand that that with few
lines of code you can actually you're
able to have your computer trading for
you. You might be at work when US market
opens
and still having your your your prop
firm challenge to be passed like it's
going to be
uh
life-changing not just from a financial
point of view, but like from literally
like
a way of trading
for many many people.
>> [snorts]
>> And I have a one of the
first guys that started following me on
social media that this guy blew up like
47 prop firm challenges. And I was like,
"Dude, I I cannot pass. It's impossible
that I pass." And we started using this
approach of like, "Let's find a strategy
that statistically is going to make you
pass. Automate it and like not only was
able to
pass his first prop firm challenge with
using this method, but he passed it
while he was at work. And I was like
that one was the thing that was was
blowing up his mind. He was like, "I was
spending 10 hours a day on front of the
screen waiting for my entry conditions
to be fulfilled." And the actual prop
firm challenge that I passed was while I
was at work and having my computer
trading for me. Because the job of the
institutional trader is 90% is research,
development, and validation. 10% is
monitoring risk and performance of your
computer trading for you.
>> Michio, thank you so much. Let's jump
off the chart.
I feel like me and you could sit here
and talk for probably 8 hours, but let's
jump off the Let's jump off the chart
and I'm going to ask you just a couple
more questions before we wrap it up
here.
Thank you so much for showing a
validated system. The cumulative
probability over time of passing a
challenge while using this system as
well as in sample out of sample
performance metrics and things of this
nature.
Audience will surely highly appreciate
it. So, Mateusz, if someone understood
everything we just talked about in this
interview and started applying it,
what could still prevent them from being
profitable or passing challenges?
>> You need to have the control over the
thinking that you know better than all
the research that you have done before
trading. Because once let's say you
spend 10 hours developing one trading
strategy, you find a trading strategy
that looks profitable, looks like it's
going to make you money, then you
automate it, then you really need to
stay away from the urge of thinking you
can do a better job. I can move this
take profit. I can move this stop loss.
I can add this extra trade that will get
a better result. No, you really did the
work before. Right now you have your
system trading for you. Just trust the
work that you have done before. And that
urge of like wanting to intervene,
wanting to I think I can do better, that
is something that you really need to
have under control and you need to
respect uh
the the the machine uh
to some degree. And that's why it's the
hard part of systematic trading. That is
the hard part of quantitative trading.
That is the hard part of this mechanical
and institutional trading. It has a
whole like trust the research that you
put down.
You did a good job. You know what you're
doing. Trust it and have let the
computer trading for you.
>> For anyone that comes straight out of
this video and goes, "I'm going to
automate." and they run their strategy,
how do they know if the strategy is
deployed and it starts doing bad? If
it's just normal drawdown or regular
variance in the return structure
or if they actually messed something up
and the strategy is overfit, it it's
garbage.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, that's that's what the Monte Carlo
is used for because Monte Carlo, when
you run the simulation, gives you
yardsticks. Like gives you, okay, you
have only a 5% probability of get
drawdown larger than $10,000
over 10 trades. So, obviously, if you
have a drawdown that is $5,000, all
good. It is within the expected
parameters. But if you have a drawdown
of $15,000 over 10 trades, then you know
that you have less than 5% probability
of getting that type of drawdown, and
you know that you need to stop the
strategy. So, you have yardsticks that
you get from the validation phase of all
your trading strategies, and they really
that is what really give you the
confidence of even knowing, okay, I know
that everything is within expected
parameters, I don't need to be worried
about it. On the other hand, once it
gets outside the expected parameters,
you need to be
more cautious and you're like, okay,
let's stop. Here, I it up.
Cannot run it live. Let's remove it. And
that's like
a skill that you always obviously you
acquire over time, but it's pure like
following a specific process, following
a specific protocol. It's like it's
nothing fancy, you just need to know
which are the steps that you need to
follow between idea generation
>> [snorts]
>> to deployment. And once you deploy, what
you need to do to monitor performance or
risk.
>> Matteo, is there any part of trading
that you think should stay
discretionary?
>> It really depends. Like some parts like
even let let's put it this way. Like
let's say
there is you want to keep being a
discretionary trader. Completely cool.
But knowing how to test what you're
doing can only add you value. Like it's
not that you need necessarily automate
every single thing that you do. But for
example, let's say you want to test a
discretionary strategy. Cool. Like try
to simplify it in a way that you can
test and you can at least see if you
have a positive drift in the past if you
apply those type of set of rules. That
can only add you value. That's why it's
a skill set that every single modern
trader should have. No matter if you
want to trade manually, no matter if
you're discretionary trading, there no
matter if
you want to automate 100% your trading
process. And that's why it is important.
It's like it's a skill set that you get,
you make it yours, and how to use it if
you want to use it to just do some
validation, if you want to use it to
just do some optimization because like
yes, you usually have a tick profit at
20 points, but you're wondering, "Okay,
but what if all the trades that I took
over the past 5 years, I used 100
points, what would be my performance?"
So really can can use it to extract
insights that
you wouldn't be able to get otherwise.
>> Matteo, is there any final piece of
advice you'd like to leave for anyone
watching that might be struggling
trading?
>> If you don't know what you're doing,
don't trade.
If you want if if if you want to trade,
first test what you're doing, understand
if you are likely or not to make money
with the strategy you're applying, and
once you find validated statistical
evidence,
that's the moment that you deploy
capital.
>> Matteo, thank you so much for coming on,
showing the data, showing a validated
strategy, the prop firm Golden Ticket.
I appreciate you coming on and it was an
absolute great time.
>> Thank you so much, brother. And uh let's
do that again.
>> IQ Capital, built by traders, for
traders. You can start your first
challenge for as little as $1. Check the
link in the description below. Terms and
conditions do apply. Thank you so much
for watching. We'll see you in the next
one.